<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DaveWave: Collaborative Gravity Wave Research on The DataWave Project</title>
    <link>http://datawaveproject.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DaveWave: Collaborative Gravity Wave Research on The DataWave Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://datawaveproject.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Post-Doc Position at LMD/ENS (Paris) </title>
      <link>http://datawaveproject.github.io/jobs/parispostdoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://datawaveproject.github.io/jobs/parispostdoc/</guid>
      <description>Responsible: François Lott in collaboration with R. Plougonven, H. Hertzog and A. Podglagen from LMD. A 2-year post doctoral position is opening at the “Laboratoire de Meteorologie Dynamique” to work on the parameterization of atmospheric gravity waves in the IPSL Climate model. The candidate will develop off-line versions of the operational subgrid scale parameterizations of gravity waves that are related to mountains (Lott and Miller 1997), convection (Lott and Guez 2013) and fronts (de la Camara and Lott 2016) and guide them with analysis field from ECMWF.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter I: The Grand Hall</title>
      <link>http://datawaveproject.github.io/post/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://datawaveproject.github.io/post/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>Three hundred and forty-eight years, six months, and nineteen days ago to-day, the Parisians awoke to the sound of all the bells in the triple circuit of the city, the university, and the town ringing a full peal.
The sixth of January, 1482, is not, however, a day of which history has preserved the memory. There was nothing notable in the event which thus set the bells and the bourgeois of Paris in a ferment from early morning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://datawaveproject.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://datawaveproject.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>Write to us with your questions, comments, and interests.
Your Name Email Address An email address is required.  Message   </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
