<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DataWave: Collaborative Gravity Wave Research on The DataWave Project</title>
    <link>http://datawaveproject.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DataWave: Collaborative Gravity Wave Research on The DataWave Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://datawaveproject.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PhD Position at Goethe Universität Frankfurt</title>
      <link>http://datawaveproject.github.io/jobs/goethe_phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://datawaveproject.github.io/jobs/goethe_phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://datawaveproject.github.io/Jobs/images/Goethe_square.png&#34; alt=&#34;tesr&#34; style=&#34;float:left;width:25%;height:25%;padding:0 25px 0 0;&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Advisor: Prof. Dr. Ulrich Achatz &lt;/h2&gt;                                           
&lt;!-- ![logo](/images/cover/Goethe_square.png) --&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://datawaveproject.github.io/pdfs/PhD_Ulrich.pdf&#34;&gt;PDF Here&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A 3-year PhD student is opening in the research group &lt;i&gt;Theory of Atmospheric Dynamics and Climate&lt;/i&gt; at the Institute of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://frankfurt.de/english/about-frankfurt&#34;&gt;Goethe University&lt;/a&gt; to be filled as soon as possible. The field of research shall be the theory of the nonlinear dynamics of atmospheric gravity waves and their efficient representation in models. The focus will be on mountain waves in the advanced parameterization framework MS-GWaM in the weather-forecast and climate code UA-ICON.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post-Doc Position at Goethe Universität Frankfurt</title>
      <link>http://datawaveproject.github.io/jobs/goethe_postdoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://datawaveproject.github.io/jobs/goethe_postdoc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://datawaveproject.github.io/Jobs/images/Goethe_square.png&#34; alt=&#34;tesr&#34; style=&#34;float:left;width:25%;height:25%;padding:0 25px 0 0;&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Advisor: Prof. Dr. Ulrich Achatz &lt;/h2&gt;       
&lt;!--  --&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://datawaveproject.github.io/pdfs/postdoc_Ulrich.pdf&#34;&gt;PDF Here&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt; A 2-year post doctoral position is opening in the research group &lt;i&gt;Theory of Atmospheric Dynamics and Climate&lt;/i&gt; at the Institute of Atmospheric and Environmental Sciences of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://frankfurt.de/english/about-frankfurt&#34;&gt;Goethe University&lt;/a&gt; to be filled as soon as possible. The field of research shall be the theory of the nonlinear dynamics of atmospheric gravity waves and their efficient representation in models. The focus will be on mountain waves in the advanced parameterization framework MS-GWaM in the weather-forecast and climate code UA-ICON.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post-Doc Position at LMD/ENS (Paris) </title>
      <link>http://datawaveproject.github.io/jobs/parispostdoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://datawaveproject.github.io/jobs/parispostdoc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://datawaveproject.github.io/Jobs/images/LMD_square.png&#34; alt=&#34;logo&#34; style=&#34;float:left;width:25%;height:25%;padding:0 25px 0 0;&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Advisor: François Lott in collaboration with R. Plougonven, H. Hertzog and A. Podglagen from LMD. &lt;/h2&gt;       
&lt;!--  --&gt;

&lt;p&gt; A 2-year post doctoral position is opening at the “Laboratoire de Meteorologie Dynamique” to work on the parameterization of atmospheric gravity waves in the IPSL Climate model. The candidate will develop off-line versions of the operational subgrid scale parameterizations of gravity waves that are related to mountains (Lott and Miller 1997), convection (Lott and Guez 2013) and fronts (de la Camara and Lott 2016) and guide them with analysis field from  ECMWF.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seasonal and Latitudinal Variability of the Gravity Wave Spectrum in the Lower Stratosphere</title>
      <link>http://datawaveproject.github.io/research/seasonal_latitudinal_variability/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://datawaveproject.github.io/research/seasonal_latitudinal_variability/</guid>
      <description>Superpressure balloon data of unprecedented coverage from Loon LLC is used to investigate the seasonal and latitudinal variability of lower stratospheric gravity waves over the entire intrinsic frequency spectrum. We show that seasonal variability in both gravity wave amplitudes and spectral slopes exist for a wide range of intrinsic frequencies and provide estimates of spectral slopes in five latitudinal regions for all four seasons, in five different frequency windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://datawaveproject.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://datawaveproject.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>Write to us with your questions, comments, and interests.
Your Name Email Address An email address is required.  Message   </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
